Nothin' but a good time.
Rock of Ages is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Adam Shankman.
A small town girl and a city boy meet on the Sunset
Strip, while pursuing their Hollywood dreams.
Sherrie Christian, played by Julianne Hough.
Drew Boley, played by Diego Boneta.
Dennis Dupree, played by Alec Baldwin.
Stacee Jaxx, played by Tom Cruise.
Lonny Barnett, played by Russell Brand.
Constance Sack, played by Malin Åkerman.
Rock of Ages is a 2012 American jukebox musical comedy film directed by Adam Shankman from a screenplay by Chris
D'Arienzo, Allan Loeb, and Justin Theroux, based on the rock jukebox Broadway musical Rock of Ages by D'Arienzo.
Produced by New Line Cinema and Corner Stone Entertainment in association with
Offspring Entertainment and Material Pictures, and distributed by Warner Bros.
Pictures, the film stars Julianne Hough and Diego Boneta (in his film debut), leading an ensemble cast that
includes Russell Brand, Alec Baldwin, Paul Giamatti, Catherine Zeta-Jones, Malin Åkerman, Mary J.
Blige, Bryan Cranston and Tom Cruise.
Like the stage musical, the film features the music of many 1980s rock artists including Def Leppard, Journey, Scorpions, Poison,
Foreigner, Guns N' Roses, Pat Benatar, Joan Jett, Bon Jovi, Twisted Sister, Whitesnake, REO Speedwagon, and others.
After the success of the stage musical, the film
rights were sold to Warner Bros.
and New Line in early 2009.
Shankman was confirmed as director in October, with D'Arienzo announced to be
adapting his book into the screenplay, later joined by Loeb and Theroux.
Originally scheduled to enter production in summer 2009 for a 2011 release, it eventually commenced production in May 2011, with Hough,
Boneta, Cruise, Brand, Baldwin, Giamatti, Zeta-Jones, Blige, Cranston, Åkerman, and the rest of the cast already filled out.
Principal photography took place between May and August of that year, with locations
including Miami, Hollywood, and Fort Lauderdale, Florida, as well as Los Angeles.
Aside from the songs, the duo of Adam Anders and Peer
Åström composed the film's incidental score.
Rock of Ages premiered at Grauman's Chinese Theatre in Los Angeles on June 8, 2012,
and was released in the United States on June 15, by Warner Bros.
The film received mixed to negative critical reviews and was a box-office bomb,
grossing only $59 million worldwide on a $75 million budget.
While criticism was aimed at its script and the lack of faithfulness to its source material, Cruise's performance
was praised, particularly for his performances of "Pour Some Sugar on Me" and "Wanted Dead or Alive".
The related film soundtrack was also well-received, debuting
at #1 on the Billboard Top Soundtracks chart.
The film explores themes of coming out, love triangle,
rock star, musical, moral conflict.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.